A Guide to the Lund Washington Letters, 1767-1790
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lund Washington Letters, 1767-1790
Library of Virginia
24160
Positive photostats, 161 leaves
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by the Mount Vernon Ladies' Association, Mount Vernon, Virginia, per Dr. Gertrude R. B. Richards, May 1954.
Biographical/Historical Information
Lund Washington was born 21 October 1737 in Stafford County, Virginia, to Townshend and Elizabeth Lund Washington. Lund Washington managed Mount Vernon for his cousin George Washington (1732-1799) while the latter was away. Lund Washington bought his estate, "Hayfield," from George Washington in 1782. That same year he married Elizabeth Foote (d. 1812) and they had two daughters who died young. Lund Washington died in July 1796.
Scope and Content Information
Letters, 1767-1790, from Lund Washington (1737-1796) of Fairfax County, Virginia, to George Washington (1732-1799) concerning Lund Washington's management of George Washington's Mount Vernon Estate and other properties. Lund Washington discusses agricultural conditions; George Washington's land dealings; buying, selling, and health of slaves; construction and repairs to farm building and the house; livestock, especially horses; George Washington's tenants; conditions in Alexandria and Fairfax County during the Revolution; Potomac River defenses; and personal news. Lund Washington mentions Martha Washington (1731-1802) several times.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Note
Originals are located at Mount Vernon, Mount Vernon Ladies' Association, APC Building/Collections Department, P.O. Box 110, Mount Vernon, Virginia 22121-0110
Contents List
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 22 March 1767, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 22 August 1767, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 5 September 1767, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 12 May 1771, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 29 September 1775, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 5 October 1775, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 15 October 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 22 October 1775, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 29 October 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 5 November 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 12 November 1775, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 14 November 1775, 6 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 24 November 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 3 December 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 10 December 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 17 December 1775, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 23 December 1775, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 17 January 1776, 6 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 25 January 1776, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 31 January 1776, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 8 February 1776, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, Cambridge, Mass., 15 February 1776, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, [7] March [1776], 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 24 December 1777, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 20 January 1778, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 4 March 1778, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 11 March 1778, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 18 March 1778, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 1 April 1778, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 8 April 1778, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 22 April 1778, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 6 May 1778, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 19 August 1778, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 2 September 1778, 8 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 20 November 1782, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 4 December 1782, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to George Washington, 11 December 1782, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 8 January 1783, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 29 January 1783, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 19 February 1783, 3 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 12 March 1783, 4 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 23 April 1783, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Mount Vernon, to General George Washington, 1 October 1783, 7 prints.
- Lund Washington to General George Washington, Mount Vernon, 6 March 1789, 2 prints.
- Lund Washington, Way Field, to George Washington, 28 April 1790, 4 prints.